Guide to the Schwabacher company records, 1894-1944 JL009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Schwabacher company records,
1894-1944
JL009
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
3.0 Linear feet
Schwabacher Bros. & Company (Seattle, Wash.)
Scope and Content
The Schwabacher company records in this collection include records of several of the enterprises in Seattle, the Stockton Milling Company in Stockton, California, and of Schwabacher Bros. of San Francisco. There were many Schwabacher brothers and cousins, involved in the many companies bearing their name. Following is a list of the companies represented in this collection and the member of the Schwabacher family apparently most closely connected with each:
Schwabacher Bros. of San Francisco: investment brokers - Louis A. Schwabacher
Schwabacher Hardware Company, Seattle- Leo S. Schwabacher
Schwabacher Bros. & Co. Inc., Seattle- Abraham Schwabacher
Schwabacher Realty Company, Seattle-
Gatzert-Schwabacher Land Company, Seattle- Frank or Sigmund Schwabacher
Stockton Milling Company-Stockton, California- Sigmund Schwabacher, president
The records and papers in the collection cover the dates 1894-1944, and consist of miscellaneous reports and letters concerning the Seattle enterprises (1910 and 1921-1923); accountant's reports and balance sheets for each of the four Seattle companies reporesented (1910-1933); minute book and cash book, as well as sundry agreements and correspondence for the Stockton Milling Company (1894-1920); and checkbooks and a trial balance for Schwabacher Bros. in San Francisco (1906-1944).
Provenance
Gift of Sam I. Schwabacher, 1956.
Access Restrictions
None.
- A. SCHWABACHER BROS.-SAN FRANCISCO, (1906-1944)
  - Checkbook, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Checkbook, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Trial balance, 1906-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- B. SEATTLE ENTERPRISES, (1909-1933)
  - GENERAL BUSINESS
    - Miscellaneous letters and reports, 1910 and 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Land assessment book, 1909-1911 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Maps and newspaper clippings, 1914-1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Tax ovaluations, 1910-1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - SCHWABACHER REALTY COMPANY
    - Reports and accounts (balance sheets, report on audit), 1913-1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - SCHWABACHER BROS. & COMPANY
    - Accountant's reports, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Reports and accounts (balance sheets), 1912-1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SCHWABACHER HARDWARE COMPANY
    - Accountant's reports, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Reports and accounts (balance sheets), 1912-1928 (Box 2, Folder 4,5)
  - GATZERT-SCHWABACHER LAND COMPANY
    - Accountant's report, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Reports and accounts (balance sheets, report on audit), 1914-1933 (Box 2, Folder 7,8)
- C. STOCKTON MILLING COMPANY, (1894-1920)
  - Minute book, 1906-1919 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cash book, 1910-1920 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Crown Flour Mills Company, 1910-1916 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Agreement with Stockton Milling Company Correspondence, 1910
  - Alsop Process Company -vs- Stockton Milling Co., 1908 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
    - Charts
  - Tax receipts, 1910-1916 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Promissory notes, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 5)